Salvador Luria Papers 1923-1992 Mss.Ms.Coll.39
American Philosophical Society
Salvador E. Luria Papers
1923-1992
Mss.Ms.Coll.39
American Philosophical Society
44.0 Linear feet
A bacteriologist from MIT, Salvador E. Luria's work with Max Delbruck on bacteriophage demonstrated that bacterial resistance to certain phages arose through genetic mutations. His later work showed that phages also mutate genetically. He received the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1969 with Max Delbruck and Alfred D. Hershey. The collection is organized into seven series: I. Correspondence, 1938-1992; IIa. Subject Files, 1938-1990; IIb. Personal Material. 1923-1991; III. Works by Luria, 1938-1987; IV. Works by Others, 1944-1990; V. Research Notes and Notebooks, 1941-1979; VI. Course Material, 1931-1991; VII. Photographs and Negatives, 1957-1982. Arrangement: Alphabetical by folder title and then chronological within each folder.
Luria, S. E., (Salvador Edward), 1912-1991
Bibliography
Luria, Salvador, General Virology (New York: Wiley and Sons, 1953). Call no.: 576.64 L97g.
Luria, Salvador, Life: the Unfinished Experiment (New York: Scribner, 1973). Call no.: 575 L975L.
Luria, Salvador, A Slot Machine, a Broken Test Tube: An Autobiography (New York: Harper and Row, 1984). Call no.: B L975s.
Luria, Salvador, Miscellaneous reprints (including a bibliography). Call no.: 574 Pam L.
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
American Association for the Advancement of Science Correspondence (2 folders) 1955-1976
American Society for Microbiology Records (18 folders) 1965-1985
Anderson, Thomas Foxen Correspondence (18 items) 1949-1970
Beadle, George Wells Correspondence (1 item) 1959
Brenner, Sydney Correspondence (4 items) 1960-1961
Carlson, Elof Axel Correspondence (3 items) 1970
Carnegie Institution of Washington Correspondence (10 items) 1957-1981
Caspari, Ernst Wilhelm Correspondence (2 items) 1957, 1959
Cohen, Seymour S. Correspondence (12 items) 1949-1957
Columbia University Correspondence (37 items) 1940-1990
Crick, Francis H. C. Correspondence (3 items) 1959, 1985
Delbruck, Max Correspondence (9 items) 1943-1972
Demerec, Milislav Correspondence (1 item) 1949
Dobzhansky, Theodosius Correspondence (8 items) 1959-1973
Dunn, Leslie Clarence Correspondence (7 items) 1956-1962
Ephrussi, Boris Correspondence (1 item) 1959
Glass, Bentley Correspondence (1 item) 1959
Hershey, Alfred Day Correspondence (27 items) 1949-1963
Lewontin, Richard Charles Correspondence (2 items) 1985
McClintock, Barbara Correspondence (3 items) 1978, 1982
Monod, Jacques Correspondence (39 items) 1957-1976
Muller, Hermann Joseph Correspondence (8 items) 1956-1962
National Academy of Sciences Records (2 folders) 1955-1986
National Research Council -- Board of Research on the Effects of Radiation Records (3 folders) 1981-1985
Nobel Prize Correspondence (8 folders) 1969
Oak Ridge National Laboratory Correspondence (10 items) 1949-1958
Olby, Robert Cecil Correspondence (2 items) 1974
Pauling, Linus Correspondence (10 items) 1957-1965
Salk Institute for Biological Studies Records (23 folders) 1965-1982
Sonneborn, Tracy M. Correspondence (7 items) 1958-1978
Stent, Gunther S. Correspondence (10 items) 1957-1981
Stern, Curt Correspondence (1 item) 1959
Wright, Sewall Correspondence (1 item) 1959
Separated Materials note
Two cassette tapes were removed from the collection ("Adventures in the Gene Trade" and "Science, Technology, and Responsibility"), along with one sound track film reel ("The Nobel Prize in Medicine: A Meeting with Dr. Alfred D. Hershey, Prof. Max Delbrück, and Prof. Salvador E. Luria), and two sound tape reels ("How Does a Virus Work?" and "Science, Technology, and Responsibility"). To retrieve these items, consult the card catalog for manuscript materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Luria Papers were donated by Salvador E. Luria in 1985 (Accession 1985-575ms). After his death, additions were made to the collection by the estate of Salvador E. Luria in 1992 (Accession 1992-1176ms), in 1993 (Accession 1993-1542ms and Accession 1993-2043ms), and in 1994 (Accession 1994-636ms and Accession 1994-695ms). Most of the material from the 1950s came from Luria's office at Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
Scope and Contents note
The Salvador E. Luria Papers (1923-1992) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Luria, papers by colleagues and students, research notes by Luria and by students, course material, and photographs, which document Luria's career as a molecular biologist. The collection is mainly in English, but there are a few items in other languages, such as Italian and French. These latter folders are marked, for example, "Some in Italian" or "In Italian," as appropriate.
The papers (94 boxes; 48.25 linear feet) are divided into eight series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1938-1992 (31 boxes; 15.5 linear feet)
Series IIa. Subject files, 1938-1990 (8 boxes; 3.75 linear feet)
Series IIb. Personal material, 1923-1991 (2 boxes; .75 linear feet)
Series III. Works by Luria, 1938-1987 (6 boxes; 2.75 linear feet)
Series IV. Works by others, 1944-1990 (23 boxes; 11 linear feet)
Series V. Research notes, 1941-1979 (10 boxes; 4.5 linear feet)
Series VI. Course material, 1931-1991 (9 boxes; 4.5 linear feet)
Series VII. Photographs, 1957-1982 (7 boxes; 5.25 linear feet)
Series I-VII. Oversize (1 box; .25 linear feet)
Arrangement note
Oversized materials follow the same series arrangement as the general collection. Cross-referencing to oversized material appears on the folders in the standard sized boxes. All photographs and negatives have been removed from Series I-V and placed in Series VII. Cross-references appear in the original series. Reprints have been moved to the printed materials collection of the APS library. If a reprint was found as an enclosure, a photocopy of the title page was filed in its place. To retrieve reprints, consult the card catalog for printed materials.
The last addition to the Luria Papers included thirteen 5.25" disks containing word processing files. These files were printed onto acid-free paper and incorporated into the collection. Since many of these files contained a date code which automatically generated the date of the document as the date of its printing, the correct date for the document (as determined from the disk directory) was written in pencil on the printed document.
Biographical/Historical note
Salvador E. Luria was born on 13 August 1912 in Turin, Italy. He received his M.D. at the University of Turin in 1935, later becoming a specialist in radiology in Rome. With the rise of fascism and anti-semitism in Italy, he left in 1938 for Paris, where he was a Research Fellow at the Institute of Radium until 1940.
At that time, as the Nazis invaded France, Luria left for the United States (later, in 1947, he became a U.S. citizen), for a position as Research Assistant in Surgical Bacteriology at Columbia University, under the auspices of the Rockefeller Foundation, where he remained until 1942. He worked during the summers with Max Delbrück in Cold Spring Harbor on bacteriophage (a virus that infects bacteria). When Delbrück went to Vanderbilt, Luria went with him as a Guggenheim fellow for one year. They continued their collaboration after Luria became an Instructor in Bacteriology at Indiana University in 1943.
Luria and Delbrück's work on bacteriophage demonstrated that bacteria resistant to certain phages arose through gene mutations. Later work by Luria showed that phages also mutate genetically. The existence of genetic recombination in phage was revealed independently by Delbrück and by Alfred D. Hershey, the latter subsequently showing that phages were composed of DNA. This work earned Luria, Delbrück, and Hershey the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1969.
At Indiana University, Luria rose from Instructor to Assistant Professor (1945-1947) to Associate Professor of Bacteriology (1947-1950). One of his graduate students was James D. Watson; it was Luria who arranged for Watson to work at the Cavendish Laboratory, where he met Francis H.C. Crick.
In 1950, Luria became Professor of Bacteriology at the University of Illinois, where he remained until 1959. During this time, he also lectured in biophysics at the University of Colorado in 1950, was the Jesup Lecturer in Zoology at Columbia University in 1950, and was the Niewland Lecturer in Biology at the University of Notre Dame in 1959.
Luria became Professor of Microbiology and Chairman of the Microbiology Committee at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (M.I.T.) in 1959. In 1964, he was made Sedgwick Professor of Biology, and then in 1970, Institute Professor. In 1972, he founded the Center for Cancer Research at M.I.T., which he directed from 1972 to 1985.
Luria was affiliated with many professional organizations during his career at M.I.T. He was a Non-Resident Fellow at the Salk Institute for Biological Studies, was on the Scientific Advisory Committee of the Massachusetts General Hospital (1965-1968), was a member of the Committee on Personnel of the American Cancer Society (1966-1971), was on the boards of the Roche Institute for Molecular Biology (1972-1979) and the Basel Institute of Immunology (1977-1979), served as Chairman for the National Research Council's Board of Research on the Effects of Radiation, and was senior scientist for the Repligen Corporation.
Luria's strong political views prompted him to take a stand on many public issues, including civil defense, nuclear arms, the Middle East, and the United States' involvement in Vietnam and Central America. In 1969, he was blacklisted by the National Institutes of Health for his political activity, which included letter-writing campaigns and newspaper advertisements.
During Luria's career, he was involved with the editing of many scholarly journals. He was Editor of Virology, Associate Editor of Journal of Bacteriology, and Section Editor of Biological Abstracts, as well as being on the editorial boards of Experimental Cell Research, Journal of Molecular Biology, American Naturalist, Photochemistry and Photobiology, Annual Review of Genetics, and Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.
Luria was a member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the American Academy of Microbiology, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the American Philosophical Society, the American Society for Microbiology (Vice President, 1966-1967; President, 1967-1968), the American Society of Biological Chemists, the American Society of Naturalists, the Genetics Society of America, the National Academy of Sciences, the Society for General Microbiology, and the Society for the Study of Development and Growth.
He received many honorary degrees, including those from Brown University, Indiana University, Providence College, Rockefeller University, Rutgers University, University of Chicago, and University of Palermo.
In addition to the Nobel Prize, Luria received the Louisa Gross Horwitz Prize in 1969 with Max Delbrück for their work on the genetics of bacteria and bacteriophage. In 1974, Luria won a National Book Award in the Sciences for Life: The Unfinished Experiment, a work which has been translated into Italian, French, Spanish, German, and Japanese. Other books that Luria published include General Virology; 36 Lectures in Biology; A View of Life; and an autobiographical work, A Slot Machine, A Broken Test Tube. He published numerous articles.
When Luria died on 6 February 1991 in Lexington, Massachusetts, he was Institute Professor Emeritus at Massachusetts Institute of Technology. He is survived by his wife, Zella Hurwitz Luria, a professor of psychology at Tufts University, and his son, Daniel David Luria, an economist.
Adelberg, Edward A; American Society for Microbiology.; Anderson, Thomas Foxen, 1911-1991; Baltimore, David; Borek, Ernest, 1911-1986; Boston Area Faculty Group on Public Issues.; Chomsky, Noam; Chovnick, Arthur; Clowes, Royston C., 1921-; Cohen, Seymour S., (Seymour Stanley), 1917-; Cohn, Melvin; Crick, Francis, 1916-2004; Davis, Bernard D., 1916-; Delbrück, Max; Dobzhansky, Theodosius Grigorievich, 1900-1975; Doermann, August H; Fondation Royaumont; Gould, Stephen Jay; Gunsalus, I. C., (Irwin Clyde), 1912-; Halvorson, Harlyn O; Hershey, A. D., (Alfred Day), 1908-; International Cell Research Organization; Jacob, François, 1920-; Lederberg, Joshua; Lwoff, André, 1902-; Magasanik, Boris; McClintock, Barbara, 1902-1992; Meselson, Matthew; Monod, Jacques; National Institutes of Health; Novick, Aaron; Pauling, Linus, 1901-1994; Salk Institute for Biological Studies.; Streisinger, George; Watson, James D., 1928-; Weigle, Jean; Wiesel, Elie, 1928-; Annual reports.; Bacteriophages-Genetics; Central America-Foreign relations-1979-; Civil defense; Laboratory notebooks; Laboratory notes; Lantern slides; Lectures; Microbial genetics; Molecular biology; Nobel Prizes; Nuclear energy; Nuclear weapons; Photoprints; Political participation; Vietnamese conflict, 1961-1975; Viral genetics
- Series I. Correspondence, 1938-1992; 15.5 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Incoming and outgoing manuscript and typescript letters, carbons, telegrams, and postcards generated throughout Luria's career. Series I is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name and then chronologically within each folder. When a correspondence file includes letters to a third party (i.e., not Luria), the name is indicated on the container list by using an indent under the folder title.
  Unidentified correspondence has been filed as "Unidentified" and is arranged chronologically. Enclosed manuscripts have been removed from this series and placed in Series III or IV as appropriate. As with the reprints, a photocopy of the title page was filed with the original letter. Cross references are also given for enclosed photographs, which have been removed to Series VII. Letters of reference are filed under the name of the person who is the subject of the letter.
  The bulk of this series covers the 1960s to the 1980s. Correspondents include molecular biologists, geneticists, biochemists, chemists, students, politicians, and some publishers. Among the topics covered in this series are: research on viral genetics; conferences; and political issues. There is a substantial amount of correspondence concerning Luria's affiliation with the Salk Institute for Biological Studies, as well as with the Fondation Royaumont, the International Cell Research Organization, and the American Society for Microbiology, among other organizations. Notes and telegrams congratulating Luria on receiving the Nobel Prize in 1969 are filed in this series under "Nobel Prize--Congratulations." Correspondence concerning Central America, nuclear arms, nuclear power, and Vietnam is filed in Series II (Subject Files) under those titles.
  Correspondents in Series I include:
  Adelberg, Edward A.
  Anderson, Thomas F.
  Baltimore, David
  Borek, Ernest
  Chomsky, Noam
  Chovnick, Arthur
  Clowes, Royston C.
  Cohen, Seymour S.
  Cohn, Melvin
  Davis, Bernard D.
  Delbrück, Max
  Dobzhansky, Theodosius
  Doermann, August H.
  Gould, Stephen J.
  Gunsalus, Irwin C.
  Halvorson, Harlyn O.
  Hershey, Alfred D.
  Jacob, François
  Lederberg, Joshua
  Lwoff, André
  McClintock, Barbara
  Magasanik, Boris
  Meselson, Matthew S.
  Monod, Jacques
  Novick, Aaron
  Pauling, Linus
  Streisinger, George
  Weigle, Jean
  Wiesel, Elie
  - Abercrombie, Robert D., 1970 (Box 1)
  - Abrahamson, Dean E., 1976 (Box 1)
  - Academy Press, Inc., 1956-1973 (Box 1)
    Jacoby, Kurt
  - Académie Royale de Médicine de Belgique, 1977 (Box 1)
    In French
  - Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei, 1965 (Box 1)
    In Italian
  - Adams, Mark H., 1949, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Mary Jane Neal, 1959-1962 (Box 1)
  - Adams, William, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Addison-Wesley Publishing Company, 1976-1982 (Box 1)
  - Adelberg, Edward A., 1960-1969 (Box 1)
  - Adesnik, Milton B., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Adler, Howard I., 1960 (Box 1)
    See also Ser.I, Microbial Genetics Bulletin
  - Adler, Julius, 1962, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Adler, Susan, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Ageno, Mario, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Ahlquist, Nancy, 1966, 1981, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Martin M., 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Alianza Editorial S.A., 1974 (Box 1)
  - Alikhanian, S.I., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Leland C., 1984 (Box 1)
  - Allende, Jorge E., 1980 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Omega Alpha, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Alsop, Joseph, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Altieri, Mario, 1982-1986, n.d. (Box 1)
    Some in Italian
  - Amati, Alexandra, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Amati, Paolo, 1964, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Ambler, Richard, 1959 (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 1)
    Edsall, John T.
    -See also Ser.III, Reflections on Democracy, Science, and Cancer
    - Folder #1, 1959-Jul. 1969 (Box 1)
    - Folder #2, Jul. 1969 (Box 1)
    - Folder #3, 1970-Jul. 1972 (Box 1)
    - Folder #4, Sep. 1972-1989 (Box 2)
  - American Academy of Microbiology, 1966-1975 (Box 2)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1955-1976; 2 folders (Box 2)
    American Association for the Advancement of Science; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Business; Cancer, chemotherapy; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Educational matters; Medical research; Political issues; Protozoan genetics; Publication; Radiation genetics
    - Folder #1, Feb.-Aug. 1955 (Box 2)
    - Folder #2, Sep. 1955-1956, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - The American Association of Immunologists, 1958 (Box 2)
  - American Cancer Society, Inc. (Box 2)
    McGrady, Patrick M.
    - Folder #1, 1951-1959 (Box 2)
    - Folder #2, 1960-1971 (Box 2)
    - Folder #3, 1972-1980 (Box 2)
    - Folder #4, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - American Chemical Society, 1952, 1955 (Box 3)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1959-1970 (Box 3)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1964-1985 (Box 3)
  - American Society for Microbiology, 1965-1985; 18 folders (Box 3)
    McClung, L.S.
    Bacterial genetics; Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Molecular genetics; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder #1, 1965-Sep. 1966 (Box 3)
    - Folder #2, Oct.-Dec. 1966 (Box 3)
    - Folder #3, Jan.-Feb. 1967 (Box 3)
    - Folder #4, Mar.-14 Apr. 1967 (Box 3)
    - Folder #5, 17 Apr.-May 1967 (Box 3)
    - Folder #6, Jun.-20 Jul. 1967 (Box 4)
    - Folder #7, Aug. 1967 (Box 4)
    - Folder #8, Sep.-Oct. 1967 (Box 4)
    - Folder #9, 1-20 Nov. 1967 (Box 4)
    - Folder #10, 22-30 Nov. 1967 (Box 4)
    - Folder #11, Dec.-15 Jan. 1968 (Box 4)
    - Folder #12, 16 Jan.-19 Feb. 1968 (Box 5)
    - Folder #13, 20 Feb.-Mar. 1968 (Box 5)
    - Folder #14, Apr.-15 May 1968 (Box 5)
    - Folder #15, 16 May-Jun. 1968 (Box 5)
    - Folder #16, Jul.-Dec. 1968 (Box 5)
    - Folder #17, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Folder #18, 1970-1985 (Box 6)
  - American Type Culture Collection, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Ames, Bruce N., 1960, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Amherst College, 1958, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Amnesty International, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Anderson, Alan, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Anderson, Clay, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Anderson, E.S., 1954-1955 (Box 6)
  - Anderson, John D., 1958 (Box 6)
  - Anderson, Thomas Foxen, 1949-1970; 18.0 Item(s) (Box 6)
    Bacterial genetics; Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Congratulations, greetings, thanks -- Horwitz Prize; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Lectures, public speaking; Recommendations; University of Pennsylvania
  - Andrewes, C.H., 1959 (Box 6)
  - Angela, Piero, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Angell, Marcia, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Annual Review of Genetics, 1985 (Box 6)
    Roman, Herschel L.
  - Aposhian, H. Vasken, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Benigno S. Aquino Memorial Foundation, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - Arber, Werner, 1959-1970, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Argentina. Embassy, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Ariotti, Piero E., 1980 (Box 6)
  - Aronson, Arthur I., 1960-1961 (Box 6)
  - Asociacion Venezolana para el Avance de la Ciencia, 1969-1971 (Box 6)
    -See also Ser.III, Science, Technology,
  - Atwood, Catharine, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Aufreiter, Eva, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Augusto, Gavotti, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Austin, Mary L., 1960-1961 (Box 6)
  - Austrian, Robert, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - Ausubel, Frederick M., 1973 (Box 6)
  - Bachelor, Paul E., 1956 (Box 6)
  - Bachmann, Barbara J., 1972-1981 (Box 6)
  - Bachrach, Uriel, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Backman, Jack, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Baer, Robert, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Baglioni, Corrado, 1970-1980 (Box 6)
  - Bah, Han-Shie, 1957-1958 (Box 6)
  - Bailey, Ethel, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Bailey, L.R., 1957 (Box 6)
  - Baker, Jeffrey J.W., 1982 (Box 6)
  - Baker, Raymond M., 1980 (Box 6)
  - Baker, Thomas I., 1964 (Box 6)
    Dushman, Miriam B.
    -See also Ser.I,
  - Baldwin, Robert L., 1986 (Box 6)
  - Baltimore, David, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    See also Ser.I, Friedman, Milton
  - Baluda, Marcel, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Bang, Frederik B., 1972 (Box 6)
  - Baquero, F., 1985 (Box 6)
  - Bard College, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Barigozzi, C., 1962-1963 (Box 6)
  - Barksdale, Lane, 1957-1964 (Box 6)
  - Baron, L.S., 1957, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Barroll, Martin, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Basel Institute for Immunology, 1974-1979 (Box 7)
  - Basic Books, Inc., 1987 (Box 7)
  - Basso, Lelio, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Bautz, Friedlinde, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Bayer, Manfred E., 1965-1986 (Box 7)
  - Bayh, Burch, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Baylor, Martha B., 1956, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Baylor College of Medicine, 1979-1981 (Box 7)
  - Beacon Press, 1961, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Beadle, George W., 1959; 1.0 Item(s) (Box 7)
    See also Ser.I, University of Chicago
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Hershey, Alfred Day
  - Beale, G.H., 1960 (Box 7)
  - Becker, Yechiel, 1961-1969 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.I, Darnell, James E.
  - Beckwith, Jonathan, 1963-1982 (Box 7)
  - Begg, R.W., 1958 (Box 7)
  - Behrens, Otto K., 1949 (Box 7)
  - Bell Laboratories, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Benedetti, E.L., 1978 (Box 7)
  - Bengelsdorf, Irving S., 1971-1974 (Box 7)
  - Ben-Gurion, Renana, 1969, 1980 (Box 7)
  - The Benjamin/Cummings Publishing Company (Box 7)
    - Folder #1, 1962-Feb. 1980 (Box 7)
    - Folder #2, Mar. 1980-1981 (Box 7)
  - Bennett, H. Stanley, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Benzer, Seymour, 1949, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Benzinger, Rolf, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Beppu, Teruhiko, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Bernardini, G., 1959 (Box 7)
    -See also Ser.I, Società Italiana di
  - Bernstein, Aleck, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Berrien, Roberta Hershkowitz, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Berrigan, Daniel, 1972 (Box 7)
    Berrigan, Philip
    -See Ser.I, Berrigan, Daniel
  - Berrigan, Philip (Box 7)
  - Berry, Edward C., 1956 (Box 7)
  - Bertani, Giuseppe, 1956-1984 (Box 7)
    See also Ser.I, Calendar, Richard
  - Bertani, L. Elizabeth, 1958, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Bertozzi, Carol, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Bestor, Arthur, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Beumer, Jacques, 1957-1962 (Box 7)
    Some in French
  - Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Birnbaum, Norman, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Bishop, Lauren J. (Box 7)
    See Ser.I, Suit, Joan L.
  - Black, Lindsay M., 1957, 1961, 1966 (Box 7)
    Siegel, Albert
  - Blackwell, James, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Blake, Roger D., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Bleck, E.E., 1974 (Box 7)
  - B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Bock, Robert M., 1958 (Box 7)
  - Boezi, John, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Boice, Lu Belle, 1959-1978 (Box 7)
  - Boicourt, Rose Mary, 1955-1957 (Box 7)
  - Bok, Sisela, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Borek, Ernest, 1957, 1969-1974 (Box 7)
  - Borghi, Bruno, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Borsellino, Antonio, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Bose, Subir, 1958, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Boston Fullbright Committee, Inc., 1976 (Box 7)
  - The Boston Globe, 1961-1986, n.d. (Box 7)
    Luria, Zella
    -See also Ser.I, Maruyama, Masao
  - Boston Latin School, 1976 (Box 7)